Indiana History mss., 1725-1973 LMC 1544 LMC 1544
Lilly Library
- Indiana History
  - Fletcher, Stephen Keyes, 1840-1897, businessman. Civil War Diary., 1862, Mar. 3-Oct. 12 -; Autograph Document Signed 93 p. 21 cm. (Bound 29)
    Published as "The Civil War Journal of Stephen Keyes Fletcher," contributed by Maxwell Keyes Fletcher, III, ed. by Perry McCandless. Indiana Magazine of History, LIV; 141-190, June 1958.
  - Diary of a Civil War Soldier of Anderson, Ind. in a letter to his brother, relating his service in Kentucky and Tennessee with the 75th regiment of Indiana infantry volunteers., 1862, July 30-1863, May 15 -; Autograph Letter 72 p. 21 cm. (Box 2)
    Gift. 1944-1945
  - Morton, Oliver Perry, 1823-1877, governor of Indiana. [Appointment of James M. Buchanan to the office of 2nd Lieutenant in the 12th Regiment of the Indiana Volunteer Militia]., 1862, Aug. 6 -; Document Signed 1 p. 33 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
    Accompanied by Autograph Letter Signed from Nell (Buchanan) Matzke, niece of James M. Buchanan, to Governor Otis Bowen, May 1, 1979, presenting him with the document.
    Gift. 1986
  - Wert, John William, 1843?-, soldier, clerk. [Civil War Diary]., 1862, Nov. 11-1863, Dec. 31 -; Autograph Document Signed [158] pp. 14.5 cm. (Box 2)
    In soft wallet-style binding.
    In ink with occasional pen decorations.
    Initialed on Nov. 25, 1863: J.W.W.
    Wert was Regimental Clerk with 100th Ind. Regiment, Co. K.
    Speaks frequently of sister Georgia.
    In another hand, note that "Willie sent this Diary home by Lieu. Henry G. Collis" and that another was sent to him by mail, 1864, Jan. 15-19.
    At end of diary, five bank entries.
    Terrell's Report lists Wert's name as West: Vol 6, page 561.
    Indiana Adjutant General's Records, Indiana State Archives, Indianapolis, enters the name as: Wert, Jno. W.
    Purchase. 1981
  - Rothert, C., fl. 1865, Aurora, Ind. Six bills of C. Rothert, Mrs. C. Rothert and Mrs. Rothert for merchandise., 1862, Nov. 25-1864, Dec. 5 -; Document 6 p. 10-25 cm. (Box 2)
  - Brice, James G., soldier, Pocket diary, 1863., 1863, Jan. 1-Dec. 31 -; Autograph Document Signed [134 p.] 17.5 cm. (Box 2)
    In wallet style binding.
    In ink.
    Signed inside back cover: James G. Brice's Book, Co. A, 13th Ind.
    Vols.
    At end of diary, notes loss of "diary from June 1861…the following are the principal dates and events…" Brice mustered in June 19, 1861 as private Mustered out July 1, 1864.
    Gift. 1988
  - Hunter, James Bradbridge, 1838?-, surgeon. Diary of an assistant surgeon of the 60th regiment, Indiana volunteers., 1863, Apr. 1-1864, Mar. 25 -; Autograph Document 96 p. 14 cm. (Bound 30)
    Contents: Diary, pp. 1-80; Accounts, pp. 81-96.
  - Royce, Edwin, fl. 1863, Huntington, Ind. To Dan Royce. He is in favor of slavery "You at home would be copy better to look after your own affairs than to have any interference [sic] with a foreign country for just as sure that you strike a lick you will rue the day and get the worse licking a country ever had.", 1863, May 10 -; Typed copy. 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
  - Indiana Infantry. 117th regt., 1863-1864. Co. I. Record of issue of clothing, and other records kept by William Baxter Hughes, captain., 1863, July 5-1867, Feb. 25 -; Autograph Document Signed 94 p. 39 cm. (Bound 31)
  - Porter, Attia, Corydon, Indiana. To John C. Andrews, Company C, 43rd regiment, Indiana volunteers, Helena, Arkansas. Morgan's visit to Corydon and vicinity., 1863, July 30 -; Autograph Letter Signed 5 p. 21 cm.; photostat. (Box 2)
    Positive Photostat of original in the possession of the Andrews family. Published in Indiana Magazine of History, LIV: 139-140, June 1958.
  - Deutsche Gegenseitige Feuer-Versicherunge-gesellschaft von Indiana. Fire insurance policy no. 158, issued to Miss Kathrina Rothert, Aurora, Ind., 1863, Aug. 27 -; Document Signed 4 p. 43 cm. (Box 5)
    Signed by Adolph Seidensticker, pres.; Frederick Ritzinger, sec.; and M. Kempf, agent. Partly printed.
  - Rollings, Robert E., 1841?-1864, farmer, soldier.; [Provost] Guards, Chattanooga, Tennessee. To William E. Rollings. Tells his father about having to build breastworks at night "for when the Reebles sees us at work they shel us". Sends a ring to his sister Susan., 1863, Sept. 9 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 pp. 34 cm. (Box 2)
    Written in ink on a page from an account ledger.
    Gift. 1982
  - Indiana infantry. 18th regt., 1861-1865. Co. H. Muster roll of Capt. William Stanley Charles, Co. H., 18th regt., Indiana foot volunteers., 1863, Sept. 15 -; Autograph Document Signed 2 p.; folio.; 53 x 78 cm. (Box 5)
    Signed: William M. Alexander, 2nd lieut.
    Gift. 1934
  - Dutton, Daniel B. Diary., 1863, Dec. - 1871 -; 14.5 cm. (Box 2)
  - Pretzinger, Joe. Diary., 1863 - (Bound 32)
  - Reed, John V., 1828-1896, "Pocket Diary for 1863," Company E, 29th Indiana Regiment (Bound 33)
  - Hire, David. Diary., 1864 -; 15 cm. (Box 2)
  - Pickerel, Jonathan. Diary., 1864 -; 14.5 cm. (Box 2)
  - Letter-book of circulars, general orders and special orders to the medical section of the 9th Indiana cavalry., 1864, Mar. 18-1865, July 16 -; Document 15 p. 32 cm. (Bound 34)
    Headquarters, Northern department, Medical director's office, Columbus, Ohio, April 2, 1864, Circular no. 1
    War department, Adjutant general's office, Washington, D.C., March 18, 1864, General orders, no. 107
    Headquarters, Northern department, Medical director's office, Columbus, Ohio, May 2, 1864, Circular no. 129
    War department, Adjutant general's office, Washington, D.C., March 30, 1864, General orders, no. 129
    Indianapolis, Ind., April 29, 1864, Special orders, [signed by] Napoleon Jackson Tecumseh Dana
    Indianapolis, Ind., April 29, 1864, Special orders no. 27 [signed by] Brig.-general Henry Beebee Carrington
    Headquarters, 9th Indiana cavalry, Pulaski, Tenn., June 2, 1864, General orders no. 8
    Christie, John M., asst. surgeon, 9th Indiana cavalry, Surgeons headquarters, 9th Indiana cavalry, Vicksburg, Miss., July 16, 1865. To Lieut. Col. Eli Lilly, commanding 9th Indiana cavalry.
  - Cox, Jabez Thomas, 1846-, lawyer, judge. Diary., 1864, Apr. 11-Aug. 29 -; Autograph Document 156 p. 14 cm. (Bound 35)
    Printed with omissions in the Indiana Magazine of History, XXXVIII; 40-54, March 1932.
  - Williams, Joshua W., 1824-1884, soldier. Civil War Diary., 1864, Sept. 24-1865, July 1 -; Autograph Document Signed [30] leaves.; 18 x 24 cm. (Box 2)
    Joshua W. Williams from Knox, Indiana, served as a private in the 58th Indiana Volunteers in Georgia and South Carolina under General William T. Sherman.
  - Meriwether, J. B., fl. 1864, U.S. Provost marshall of Indiana. 2nd district. Draft notice to Ahi Leonard, ordering him to report at Jeffersonville, Ind. on Oct. 10, 1864., 1864, Sept. 27 -; Document Signed 1 p. 16 cm. (Box 2)
    Gift. 1914
  - Smith, Edward, fl. 1864, soldier. Burnside Barracks, Indianapolis, Ind. To William Wright. Refers to the 1864 election and corruption of polls in Indiana., 1864, Nov. 2 -; Autograph Letter Signed 4 p. 23 cm. (Box 2)
  - Miesse, B.B. Diary., 1863 - (Bound 36)
  - Shelby County bond, 2 May 1864 (Box 2)
  - Long, David S. Diary., 1865, Jan. 1-July 11 -; Autograph Document Signed 68 p. 22.2 cm. (Box 2)
    In pencil.
    Black wallet-style binding.
    Covers last six-months of the war.
    Long mustered in Aug. 16, 1862, as private.
    Mustered out July 1, 1865, as corporal.
    Several pages of expenses, accounts and fragments fill rest of volume.
    Purchase. 1997
  - Harrison County notarial bond for $1,000, 4 Feb. 1865 (Box 2)
  - Ferree, John C., 1839-, soldier. Civil War Diary as a member of Co. D., 29th Indiana Infantry while stationed at Chattanooga, Tennessee, Mar. 10-May 9, Dalton, Georgia, May 9-June 26, and during the process of being discharged., 1865, Mar. 10-July 2 -; Autograph Document Signed 47 p. 15 cm. (Bound 37)
    Contains also miscellaneous memoranda as late as December 6, 1868.
    Gift. 1954
  - Johnson, Henry, soldier, Camp near Goldsboro, N.C. To Anthony Johnson. News of fall of Richmond and about the 87th regiment., 1865, Apr. 6 -; Autograph Letter Signed 4 p. 22 cm.; photostat. (Box 2)
    Gift. 1962
  - Morgon, Will H., soldier, medicine salesman. Near Hanover, Jefferson Co., Ind. To "Dear Ma". Comments on the assassination of Abraham Lincoln, the succession of Andrew Johnson to the presidency, his success as a medicine salesman, and his escorting "Miss Smith" to church., 1865, Apr. 17 -; Autograph Letter Signed 3 pp. 25 cm. (Box 2)
    Morgan's first name derived from his n.d. letter in Indiana History mss.
  - Wilson, James, 1825-1867, Congressman. Quartermaster's dept., U.S.A., Indianapolis, Ind. Ordering the officer commanding Co. H., 18th regiment, Indiana volunteers, to charge John H. Back, private, $3.71 for his transportation from Indianapolis to Columbus, Ohio., 1865, May 3 -; Document Signed, 5 items, 1 p. 20 cm. (Box 2)
  - Jessup, L. B. History of the 24th Indiana during the Civil War., 1865 -; 140 p. 33.5 cm. (Box 2)
    Two folders. Manuscript and typescript included.
    Purchase. 2000.
  - Jessup, L.B. History of the 24th Indiana during the Civil War transcript, 1865 (Box 2)
  - Reddin, F.M. Diary., 1865, May - 1866, Jan. (Bound 38)
  - Teacher's licenses issued to James Dillard Yager in Morgan County, Indiana, November 18, 1865, August 17, 1867, September 23, 1871, August 24, 1878, August 28, 1880., 1865, Nov. 18-1880, Aug. 28 -; 5 Documents Signed 5 p. 22 – 29 cm. 5 items. (Box 2)
  - Jessup, L.B. History of the 24th Indiana during the Civil War. (Box 2)
  - Harrison County circuit court marriage license, 22 Jan. 1866 (Box 2)
  - Harrison County surety bond, 28 Aug. 1866 (Box 2)
  - Harrison County marriage license, 14 Jan. 1867 (Box 2)
  - Harrison County circuit court marriage certificate, 23 May 1867 (Box 2)
  - Milligan, Lambdin P., 1812-1899, lawyer, complaint. Lambdin P. Milligan vs. James R. Slack and others in the Court of Common Pleas, Huntington County, Ind., 1868, May -; Document 44 p. 32 cm. (Box 2)
  - Phelps, Abraham M., 1798-, merchant. Newburgh, Ind. To John B. Handy. Reminding him "of the necessity of legislative action in reference to the Academy property.", 1869, Jan. 12 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 25 cm. (Box 2)
    Signed: J. E. Bates for A. M. Phelps.
  - Switzerland County "notarial bond" [surety bond], 25 Apr. 1871 (Box 2)
  - Vinnedge, Samuel J., fl. 1877, dealer in lumber. Letter copybook leaves of lumber business in Kokomo, Ind., 1876, Apr. 6-1877, Jan. 10 -; Autograph Letter Signed, 9 items, (copies) pp. 7, 10-18, 20-21, 23-29, 31-37, 40-42, 45-46, 48-50, 52, 55. 28 cm. (Box 2)
    Accompanied by Autograph Letter Signed, Sept. 4, 1876. (1 p. 24 cm).
    8 miscellaneous financial memoranda. (15-21 cm).
  - Fretageot, A. H. to Hough, Daniel. Regarding works published at New Harmony, Ind., 1876, Dec. 5 -; 1 ms. Autograph Letter Signed. 21.5 cm. (Box 2)
  - Gondring, John, 1829-1916, justice of the peace, businessman. Docket No. One [for Westchester Township, Porter County, Bound Indiana]., 1876-1885 -; Autograph Document Signed [233] pp. 34 cm.; bound. (Bound 39)
    Inscribed: John Gondring, J. P., Chesterton, Ind., 1876.
    In several hands.
    Index of cases.
    First entry for cases, 1878, Dec. 21 (page 1) and last entry, 1885, Aug. 28 (page 218).
    Marriages: 1877, Mar. 11-1883, Oct. 12 (pages 208-210).
    Inventories of effects: pages 75, 87-88, 94-95.
    Occasional receipts mounted in volume.
    Laid in volume: Power of attorney to Gondring by Bridget A. O'Connor, 1885, Sept. 21.
  - Class of, Indiana State University. Album., 1878 (Bound 40)
  - Lockyear [family], near Evansville, Indiana. Diary., 1878, Jan. 1-1891, June 28 -; Autograph Document 3 vols. 32.2 cm. (Box 8)
    Writer undetermined; apparently a daughter of Theresa and William Henry Lockyear.
    Preliminary pages of vol. 1 contain accounts, 1829-1835.
  - Waterman, Luther Dana, 1830-1918, physician. Phantoms of life: verse, by Aplin Dana (Luther Dana Waterman.) Indianapolis, Ind., 1878. Printed (abridged) in 1883. G.P. Putnam's sons, N.Y. for the Author., Autograph Document Signed 317 p. [i.e. 314 p.] 19 cm. (Bound 41)
    Printed version: Luther Dana Waterman, Phantoms of life. N.Y., Putnam, 1883.
  - Banta, David Demaree, 1833-1896, dean Indiana University law school. Manuscripts decisions. Preserved for the private use of the writer., 1880-1897 -; Autograph Document 514 p.; 14 x 23 cm. (Bound 42)
    Bound in brown-beige leather.
    In black and blue ink on white paper.
    On the title page is the embossed stamp of the Indiana University Library.
    Verso of title page is accession no. 23807.
    Library records show accession date as Jan. 5, 1897.
    Laid in is a postcard to D. D. Banta from John M. Godown, secretary, of Indianapolis, dated Sept. 10, 1880.
    Found in the Law School Library. 1969
  - DePauw university, Greencastle, Ind. Board of trustees. Resolution on the death of Henry Smith Lane., 1881 -; Autograph Document Signed, 2 items, 2 p. 32 cm.; xerox copies. (Box 2)
    Accompanied by: Lane, Mrs. Joanna M. (Elston), (Mrs. Henry Smith Lane) To James C. Yohn and others, Crawfordsville, Ind., July 29, 1881. Thanks them for above resolution and corrects biographical error. (Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 19 cm.)
  - Jenckes, Joseph Sherburn, 1804-1888, lawyer. Terre Haute, Ind. To Theophilus Adam Wylie, Bloomington, Indiana. Requests that his son, Joseph Shelburne Jenckes, Jr., be awarded honorary D.D., 1882, July 20 -; Autograph Postcards. 1 p. 13 cm. (Box 2)
  - Fletcher, William Baldwin, 1837-1907, physician. Indianapolis, Ind. To Valette Miller, Indianapolis, Ind. Thanking her for some roses., 1883, Feb. 23 -; Letter Signed 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
  - Gray, Joseph, 1830-, farmer of Cass County, Indiana. Time book for farm labor., 1883, Apr. 2-1888, Mar. 7 -; Autograph Document, 6 items, 14 p., 179 p. 30 cm. (Bound 43)
    Pp. 75-78, 115-118, 143-148, 161-164, 167-178 missing.
    Parts of Pp. 1-2 and 5-6 of the preliminary paging and Pp. 27-28 and 33-34 of the main paging missing.
    Bills and receipts and one lease of land laid in.
    Gift. Source and date unknown
  - Cobb, Thomas Reed, 1828-1892, congressman. Washington, D.C. To Henry Davis. "Bill passed the House … to place you on the pension roll.", 1885, Jan. 10 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 23 cm. (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. To Henry Davis, Bedford, Indiana. "Will use my best endeavors to have your [pension] bill reported favorable.", 1885, Jan. 15 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. To Henry Davis, Bedford, Indiana. "I will request the Committee of Pensions to delay action on your application.", 1885, Jan. 17 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 21 cm. (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. To Henry Davis, Bedford, Indiana. "Your pension begins on the date of the signing of the bill.", 1885, Feb. 17 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. To Henry Davis, Bedford, Indiana. "You will be notified … by a certificate from the Pension Office that your claim has been allowed.", 1885, Mar. 6 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 20 cm. (Box 2)
  - Herndon, William Henry, 1818-1891, law partner of Abraham Lincoln. History of this book., 1886, May 18 -; Autograph Document Signed 1 p. 16 cm. (Box 2)
    Reproduced in Rufus Rockwell Wilson, What Lincoln Read, Washington, D.C., Pioneer Publishing Company, 1932, opposite page 36 (Lilly ?).
    The book referred to is The Revised laws of Indiana, 1824, belonging to David Turnham and read by Abraham Lincoln. Accompanied by letters with envelopes of G. W. Turnham, Evansville, Indiana, to William Henry Townsend, 1890-1964, lawyer, dated 1923, Apr. 21 and May 10, the latter enclosing the facsimile of a letter of Abraham Lincoln to David Turnham, Oct. 23, 1860.
    Removed from The Revised laws of Indiana…Corydon, Printed by Carpenter and Douglass, 1824 (Lilly KFI3030.A2 1824 Vault 1). 1975
  - Indiana Univ. Preparatory Dept. Honor Scholarship to Grant Teel, 1886, June 7 (Box 2)
    Issued to Teel as second-best student of the class of 1886. Printed document, filled in and signed by the Principal James K. Beck, President David S. Jordan, Assistant President James A. Woodburn, and Secretary William W. Spangler. Has embossed seal of Indiana University.
    Gift. 1989.
  - Columbus, Hope & Greensburg Railroad. Plat of proposed extension on east side of Columbus, Indiana., 1886, Sept. 6 -; Autograph Document; 74 x 209 cm. (Box Map Case)
    In blue, black, and red ink.
    Shelved on Level 2.
    Map Case.
  - Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901, pres. U.S. Indianapolis, Ind. To "My dear Sir". "We need your active earnest co-operation in the campaign. If the infamous attempt to disfranchise the non-Democratic voters of the state is ever to be defeated it must be done this year.", 1886, Oct. 26 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
    On United States Senate letterhead.
    Appears to be a facsimile.
    Gift. 1994
  - Kellogg, Miner Kilbourne, 1814-1889, artist. Brief notes for an autobiography., 1886 -; Xerox copy of Autograph Document Signed 67 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
    The last two lines of page 15 through page 40 except for the last two line of page 40 were printed with slight variations in the Indiana Magazine of History, LXIV, pp. 45-64, 1968.
  - TenBrook, Andrew, 1810-1889, Indiana Legislature, farmer. Autobiography., Xerox copy of Autograph Document 33 p. 36 cm. (Box 2)
    In the hand of Cora TenBrook, Andrew's daughter. Account dictated by her father.
    Printed with slight variations in the Indiana Magazine of History, LXI, pp. 9-30, March, 1965.
    The original document is in the John T. Campbell Papers, Indiana Division, Indiana State Library, Indianapolis, Indiana.
  - Lieber, Carl, fl. 1890, Discourse on William Dale Owen's immigration bill, delivered at the Soziale Turnverein, Indianapolis, Ind., 1890, Mar. 16 -; Autograph Document 10 p. 23 cm. (Box 2)
    In German script.
  - Wylie, Theophilus Adam, 1810-1895, educator. Note concerning qualifications of Professor Joseph P. Naylor., 1890 -; Autograph Document 1 p. 17 cm. (Box 2)
    Inscribed on envelope addressed to T. A. Wylie and postmarked Jan. 9, 1890.
    Published with slight variation in Wylie, Indiana University, its history …. Indianapolis 1890 (Lilly LD2518.W98) pages 163-4.
    Removed from Abraham Ortelius, Theatri Orbis Terrarvm Parergon.
    Antverpiae, ex Officina Plantiniana, 1624 (Lilly G1006.P228 1624). 1981
  - To Mrs. Clem Cook, 1894, Sept. 14 (Box 2)
    A Western Union Telegraph with envelope sent to Dayton, Ohio, with the message: "Baring Me, Father died today telegraph me Fort Wayne if you will come. Dan"
    Gift. 2005.
  - Wylie, Theophilus Adam, 1810-1895, educator. Notes and comments analyzing Theatri Orbis Terrarvm Parergon by Abraham Ortelius., 1894 -; Autograph Document 5 leaves. 31-26.5 cm. (Box 2)
    In pen and pencil on lined paper.
    Volume inscribed: T. A. Wylie 1894
    Removed from Ortelius, Theatri Orbis Terrarvm Parergon. Antverpiae, ex Officina Plantiniana, 1624 (Lilly G1006.P228 1624). 1981
  - Winsor, Abner, 1812?-, pioneer of Steuben County, Ind. Personal recollections of early days in Steuben County, Ind., 1895, June 19 -; Typed Document 5 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
    Typescript prepared by Loretta Sanders, County Auditor, Steuben County, Ind., Angola, Ind.
  - Macy, Albert William, 1853-, author. Western Springs, Ill. To Dr. Jarvis J. Johnson. Comments on his article about the burial of Watson Brown which was reprinted in Sunday's Indianapolis Journal. "Is it about accurate?", 1895, June 25 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 pp. 20.5 cm. (Box 2)
    Appended is an undated reply from Jarvis J. Johnson who would rather that Macy had said: "Martinsville [is] a beautiful little city of ca 4000 pop nestling at the base of White river hills having the best medicinal waters in America."
    Removed from the Lilly Correspondence, Lilly Library, Indiana University. 1978
  - Rogers, Bruce, 1870-1957, book designer. Caledonia Cottage, Brookline, To Joseph William Piercy, 117 E. Michigan St., Indianapolis, Ind. Offers congratulations on the "notice of the recent increase of population in Indianapolis"., 1895, Oct. 9 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 pp. 15.5 cm. (Box 2)
    Accompanied by envelope.
    Gift. 1983
  - McCulloch, Susan Maria (Man), 1818-1898. Recollections., 1895-1898; Xerox copy of Typed Document [72] pp. 33 cm. (Box 2)
    Prepared between 1895 and 1898.
    Second generation xerox copy of xerox of original document.
    Originally located in Allen County-Fort Wayne Historical Society which secured it from Vernon Hiscox, heir to John Ross McCulloch, grandson of Hugh and Susan Maria (Man) McCulloch.
  - Indiana infantry 26th regiment satin ribbon for reunion of the 26th Regt. of the Indiana Volunteers, 1861-1866, at Indianapolis, 1896, Sept. 12 (Box 2)
    Satin ribbon accompanied by clipping of poem entitled "Song" of five, four-line stanzas beginning: "Oh, my love has an eye of the softest blue."
    Removed from Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Indiana (W.H. Terrell), in 8 vols. Indianapolis, 1865. (Lilly E506.2 .I39 1865).
  - Swearingen, Grace. Scrapbook of newspaper and magazine clippings, pictures, stamps, etc. of the Spanish-American War, World War I, and miscellaneous other subjects., 1898-1932 -; Document 102 p. 36 1/2 cm. (Bound 44)
  - McGinnis, Horace, Martinsburg, Indiana. To Willard Voylis, Salem, Indiana. Origin of word "Hoosier"., 1899, Jan. 9 -; Autograph Letter Signed, 5 items, 5 p. 20 cm. (Box 2)
    1) Henry Jordan, Memorandum of an interview with Soloman Wynn at Corydon, Indiana September 1899. (Autograph Document 9 p. 26 cm).
    2) "The Name Hoosier". n.d. (Autograph Document 1 p. 18 cm.)
    3) Report of Aaron Wood's account of the derivation of the word "Hoosier". n.d. (Autograph Document 1 p. 18 cm.)
    4) Account of the newspaper named Hoosier and its editor John Wilson Osburn. n.d. (Autograph Document 3 p. 18 cm).
    5) Eleven mounted newspaper clippings on the word "Hoosier".
    Purchase. 1915
  - Nicholson, Meredith, 1866-1947, author. Denver, Colorado, and Indianapolis, Indiana. To Mrs. Eugenie C. (Kountze); His activities., 1901, May 16-June 10 -; 6 Autograph Letters Signed, 6 items, 30 p. 16-18 cm. (Box 2)
    Signed: M. N.
    Letters of May 16, 20, 31; June 6 and 10, 1901 from Denver; undated letter from Indianapolis, Ind.
    Gift. Source unknown. 1959
  - School registers for School District No. 7, Plain Township, Kosciusko County, Indiana., 1902-1905 - (Box 2)
    Transfer. Source unknown. April 1987.
  - Royal Templars of Temperance. Insurance policy of Laura Phillips, member of Terre Haute Council No. 2 of Indiana., 1903, Jan. 31 -; Document Signed 2 p. 46 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
    Purchase. 1952
  - Smith, Hubbard Madison, 1820-1907, physician. 523 Main Street, Vincennes, Indiana. To Mrs. Theresa Voss Smith, Indianapolis, Ind. Sending a book of poems in which he hopes she will find "some sentiments and expressions responsive" to her own., 1905, Nov. 21 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 23 cm. (Box 2)
    Found by the donor in a copy of Smith's At Midnight and Other Poems of which Lilly Library also has a copy (Lilly PS3537.M48 A7)
  - , William, 1866-1937, secretary to Pres. Theodore Roosevelt. The White House, Washington, D.C. To Addison Clay Harris, Fletcher's Bank Building, Indianapolis, Ind. On behalf of President thanks him for book., 1907, June 5 -; Typed Letter Signed 1 p. 23 cm. (Box 2)
    Mounted on inside of front cover of Lilly Library copy of Branson L. Harris' Some recollections of my boyhood … Indianapolis, The Hollenbeck press, 1907